<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 3 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Jeanne Ferrante (ETS) -->
<!-- Definitions from http://www.glaucoma.org/learn/glossary.html -->
<vdex profileType="glossaryOrDictionary" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsvdex_v1p0"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imsvdex_v1p0 imsvdex_v1p0.xsd"
    orderSignificant="false" language="en">
    <vocabName>
        <langstring>Glossary of Terms for Item Statistics</langstring>
    </vocabName>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>D-Parm</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>IRT d parameter</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A measure of the dispersion of the item computed using IRT method.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>Score_Conversion</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>Score Conversion Table</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>Raw scores and their corresponding converted values (e.g. the values to be
                used in score reports).</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>AIS</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>Average Item Score</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A group-dependent measure of item difficulty. Equal to the mean of the item
                scores for a group of individuals. For a rights-only dichotomously scored test,
                equivalent to the percent answering the item correctly (P-value).</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>A-Parm</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>IRT a parameter</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>Index of item discrimination based on item response theory.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>B-Parm</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>IRT b parameter</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>Index of item difficulty based on item response theory.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>C-Parm</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>IRT c parameter</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>The lower asymptote of the item response function. Generally an index of
                guessing, i.e., the probability of getting the item correct for very low ability examinees.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>P-value</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>P-value</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A group-dependent measure of item difficulty. It is equal to the percent
                answering the item correctly.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>PHI</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>Phi-coefficient</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A group-dependent measure of item discrimination, Phi is the correlation of
                two dichotomous variables. In item analysis, it is generally the correlation between
                getting an item right or wrong and some dichotomous variable, e.g., pass, fail.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>rbis</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>r-biserial</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A group-dependent measure of item discrimination, r-biserial is an estimate
                of the biserial correlation between a latent continuous variable hypothesized to
                underlie performance on a dichotomous item (i.e. item score) and a criterion which
                is a variable than can take many possible values, such as total score on the test.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>PTbis</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>r-pointbiserial</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>A group-dependent measure of item discrimination, r-pointbiserial is the
                point biserial correlation between the score on a dichotomous item and a criterion
                which is a variable than can take many possible values, such as total score on the test.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
    <term>
        <termIdentifier>Polyserial</termIdentifier>
        <caption>
            <langstring>Polyserial</langstring>
        </caption>
        <description>
            <langstring>The polyserial correlation is the generalization of the biserial correlation
                for use with either dichotomous or polytomous items. For example, it may be the
                generalized form of the correlation with a criterion. It is the correlation of the
                item score with some continuous variable, usually the total score on the test.</langstring>
        </description>
    </term>
</vdex>
